COLIN GOODALE

Chicago, IL 60657

Phone: 312-989-5904 | Email: colingoodale@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/colin-goodale-b551b379/

Github: https://github.com/colingoodale
Portfolio: https://www.colingoodale.com

SUMMARY

I am an accomplished MERN Stack developer. I am also a polyglot, with experience in Java, Python, C#, C++. I've built and deployed professional websites, apps, and microsystems using Node.js. I have extensive experience with the architecture of complex applications, built from the ground up. When it comes to navigating the difficulties of building something from a starting point zero, I'm completely confident that I can deliver results. Not only that, but I'm an educator with Northwestern University at the instructor level for professional developers. I work with a program that has allowed me to train recent grads, junior devs, and newcomers to become full stack engineers. I've been happy to guest teach at NYU, Princeton, and Berkley to help young developers and career transitioning adults the architectural skills that allow them to be competitive in this market.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Skills: Node.js, Java, C#, Python, PHP, Express, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, GIT, Github, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, Angular.js, Mongoose.js, Sequelize, Nodemailer.js, Slick.js, Project Management, Team Development, Individual Coaching, Accountable Data Recording, Team KPI Analysis

Applications: ragnarresearch.com

PROJECTS

Porch Pass |

- I managed and constructed the architecture for a rental application/web portal.
- Created a new business backend to support growing needs in rental markets in Texas and Arizona
- Led the design team/dev team in creating an informational site, application algorithm, and backend portal for managing paperwork, property rental, and home services
- Architected, managed, and contributed to the implementation of complex APIs including credit reporting, bank information/transactions, scheduling, and budgeting.
- Realized a system that incorporated many classes of users and oversaw the technical security of both the front end applications and backend network
- Architected system of servers that performed critical tasks to accomplish a microsystem architecture and create global security protocols

Braustin Mobile/Braustin Homes | Itunes/Android app stores

- React Native application in which I was the sole contributor
- I built a robust solution for customers to send their identification and legal paperwork for purchasing a home
- This also encompassed services with relation to their warranty as well as paid services that the company would provide for maintenance/repair
- Developed new business application for multiple home buyers that allowed for easier sales to landlords purchasing multiple homes
- Handled all QA and testing which led to a high percentage rate of successful transfer pictures and files up to 30-50 images/pdf files
- Managed and performed all maintenance

portal.braustin.com | https://findmymobilehome.com/

- I developed the architecture for a CRM, Document Generation Engine, Delivery/Service Portal with another architect
- I contributed vital code from inception of the project through late phase deployments and was crucial to maintenance of the project when it was live
- Was responsible for tech stack decisions including Vendors/critical APIs
- Managed UI/UX redesign that greatly improved sales/service team productivity as well as provided recursive bank ready documents

findmymobilehome.com | https://findmymobilehome.com/

- Developed Security protocol using the WP set of database management tools
- Contributed to Gatsby/React project with stabilizing features, bug reports/repairs, and new feature requests

RagnarResearch.com | https://github.com/colingoodale/ragnar3.0 | ragnarresearch.com

- Current client website that I have built and maintained
- Website performs delivery an average of 1.4 second, half the speed of Google Performance Benchmarks
- Makes use of Slick Slider, Nodemailer.js, Express, Sequelize

Escape Chicago | https://github.com/colingoodale/EscapeChicago | Escape Chicago

- Current client website that I have built and maintained
- Makes use of Slick Slider, Nodemailer.js, Express, Sequelize

EXPERIENCE

Software Lead/Senior Software Engineer Braustin Mobile Homes

2020 – Present

Chicago, IL

I delivered Mobile applications and led a team of 4 engineers in creating multiple environments that incorporated a complex system of mobile applications and cloud based web applications.

Key Accomplishments:

- In correspondence with Senior Architect, I created and implemented the Architecture for a system that incorporated communication between mobile, web, and back end applications
- Organized our team for production and scaling, including establishing principles of economic decision making, deployment schedules/QA operations, and managed team workflow/production road map

Full Stack Program Instructor NorthwesternIllinois University

2018 - Present

Chicago, IL

I teach sessions with students who are developing technical knowledge in the MERN fullstack bootcamp. We teach our students the Node.js framework to teach them how to create operable back ends and front ends.

Key Accomplishments:

 I have graduated multiple classes of individuals who have gone on to get their first jobs in this industry. I have worked with many students who entered the job market as Juniors, but have also worked with Junior level employees to get acquainted with a Senior level development needs.

Independent Web Developer

2018 – Present

Chicago, IL

I currently create and develop web applications to achieve client goals. Experienced in multiple deployments and basic cyber-security provisions. I also have experience debugging and tuning a website for speed and different device specifications. Prepare and maintain websites for basic SEM needs.

Key Accomplishments:

 Developed light cloud applications to customer specifications and with the ability to achieve marketing needs.

Senior Account manager

2017 - 2018

Breather Chicago, IL

I sold a retail based solution as a more robust SaSS product to large companies. Integrated local needs to direct the development of our major tech property. Developed a program that allowed large companies to rent remote spaces out on demand.

Key Accomplishments:

- Grew local Chicago market from -135% margin to 46% in 6 month period
- Helped define and realize account structure that led to a robust product that companies could utilize on demand

Account Acquisition Manager AdGooroo

2015 – 2017

Chicago, IL

I led a small team in acquiring fortune listed companies with our search data. I was a critical component in understanding our technological capabilities, the needs of clients, and how to pair those two in the eyes of decision makers.

Key Accomplishments:

- Successfully led small international team in acquiring high value B2B clientele
- Personally signed IBM, Walmart, TESCO, and Best Buy among other clientele across all major business categories

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Developer Bootcamp: Northwestern University, Chicago, IL A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Arts: Western Illinois University, Macomb, IL